# Aryan Mehta



am.career11@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/am161



07446048446



https://www.aryanmehta.dev

## **Summary**

Experienced UI/Front-End Developer with 2 years of experience building pixel perfect complex web applications from a given Figma design.

I have experience dealing with RESTful APIs and have the understanding of fetching and manipulating data on the server.

I have built API endpoint for a personal project, where I used Express.js and MongoDB and was successfully able to do CRUD operations using it.

Proficient experience in state management; using hooks or libraries.

Trained in HTML5, JavaScript ES6+, CSS, TailwindCSS, SCSS, BEM, React, React Router, Redux, React Query, and Axios.

### **Experience**



#### 🦄 Frontend Developer

Plume - Learning Technology Agency

Jun 2022 - Dec 2022 (7 months)

(7 months)

- Built an e-learning platform estimated to be used by 100,000+
- users as well as a platform for admins to manage the content.
- Created reusable components and hooks which resulted in quicker frontend development.
- Integrated RESTful API endpoints, which were called using Axios and React Router.
- Managed state with hooks and React Router.
- Clean reusable code
- Conditionally rendered content
- Responsive



#### Frontend Developer

Learn&Co Ltd | Language Agency

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022 (7 months)

Worked in a team following agile workflow.

- Created reusable components and custom hooks which reduced the code significantly.
- Used Axios for API calls and hooks to manage state.
- Managed page routes using React Router.

**Projects** 

Invoice App

React.js, Google Firebase and TailwindCSS

Live: https://am1553.github.io/invoice-app/ Live: https://github.com/am1553/invoice-app

- Converted a Figma design to completely functional advance CRUD web application.
- Used TailwindCSS for styling and responsive layouts.
- Used hooks for data fetching and manipulation.
- Managed state using hooks and ContextApi.
- Used advanced folder structure for production level applications.

- Used external libraries for calendar and firebase for data storage.
- Created PRs and branches for git management.

## **Education**

## **The Open University**

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science 2021 - 2024

## **Skills**

agile • api • approach • bsc • com • content management • css • functional • javascript • mathematics